does Jordan recommend varil embolization
before looking at laparoscopic varic
colomy oh man yeah and I never did veric
casil stuff as a urologist myself
because I hate it um and because if you
don't do it the right way they'll often
come back and I would honestly say
neither of those are great options um
laparoscopic probably might be better
than imization imization often fail um
you know they work temporarily um and
kind of the same thing with the
laparoscopic ver vasectomy they're only
clipping the main gatal vein you're not
getting down down stream Upstream
actually closer to the testicle where
there's multiple veins coming off you
know they all conglomerate into one but
I would say the number one method for
truly fixing a verical would be a
microscopic vericel ectomy and so you
get a surgeon that's that's good on the
microscope and they do like a
subinguinal incision kind of like if you
having an inguinal hernia uh surgery and
they'll tie off each individual vein uh
coming you know the peniform plexus
veins coming off the test and um that
seems to be best results with least
likelihood of coming back with a hydro
seal or something like that because if
you just take everything you're getting
the lymphatics in there too see them
well then that's going to affect the
drainage and so I think you're much
better off now if a guy just wants to
try it imization obviously safer you're
not you're really you're not going under
probably even a general aesthetic for
that so the risk is going to be a little
lower um so you know you it just may not
work and then people are mad because
they're like well it failed but as long
as you know going in hey it may not work
forever I think that's fine
[Music]